A Guide to the Papers of the Institute of Public Affairs, University of Virginia, 1927-1953
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Series II: Original Manuscripts-Round Table, Open Forum, Special Conference (Box 17-53)
  - Evening Addresses
    - "Our Present Military Policy," Colonel Stanley D. Embrick; "The Monroe Doctrine," Hon. Hugh Gordon Miller; Closing Address, Dr. Charles G. Maphis 1929 August 16 (Box 20)
    - "Report of the President of 'The Committee for Education in Citizenship'" n.d. (Box 20)
    - Department of Taxation and Finance, Appendix C 1929 (Box 20)
  - Round Table: "Country Life of the Nation"
    - Introduction, Dr. Wilson Gee; "The Basis of a Permanently Prosperous Agriculture," Dr. James Ernest Boyle; "Farm Group Activities in the South," Eugene Cunningham Branson; "Wealth Retention in the Rural South," Charles Ernest Allred 1929 August 5 (Box 20)
    - "The Eastern shore of Virginia Produce Exchange," Benjamin T. Gunter; "Farm Cooperative Activities," Dr. E. C. Branson 1929 August 7 (Box 20)
    - "Little Country Towns and What They May Do for Surrounding Trade Areas," Newell L. Sims; "Housing the Farm Family," Ms. Julia D. Connor; "The Movement of Farm Population: Its Economic Causes and Consequences," Ernest Charles Young; "Farmer Controlled Commodity Marketing Essential to Prosperous Farming," Benjamin F. Yoakum; "The Farm Family: Its Contribution to the Nation," Miss Florence Elizabeth Ward; "The Extent and Significance of Farm Migration," Leon Edgar Truesdell 1929 August 9 (Box 21)
    - "Social Vision and Rural Education," Fannie Wyche Dunn; "Fundamental Needs of the Country Schools," Edgar Wallace Knight 1929 August 14 (Box 21)
    - "The Opportunity of the Small Town: A Study of Town and Country Relations," John Harrison Kolb 1929 August 16 (Box 21)
    - Summary 1930 (Box 21)
  - Round Table: "The Task of the Country Church"
    - Table of Contents n.d. (Box 21)
    - "The Country Church and Public Affairs," Rev. Henry W. McLaughlin, D.D.; "Discovery of the Country Community," Dr. Henry N. Morse; "Discoveries in Rural Virginia," Charles Horace Hamilton; "Functions of the Country Church," Dr. J. W. Perry; "A Country Church Program," Rev. C. Morton Hanna; "United Churches Do Not Solve the Country Church Problem," Dr. J. W. Jent; "United Churches Solve the Country Church Problem," Dr. William R. King; "The Country Minister," Dr. John C. Siler; "Training of the Rural Minister," Dr. F. D. Goodwin; "Medical Care for Country People," Dr. W. S. Rankin; "The Biblical Program of Healing," Dr. Jesse C. Rowan; "The Ministry of Healing in the Country," Rev. Henry McLaughlin, D.D.; "The Recreational Life of Country Young People," C. A. Montgomery; "A Country Church Solves the Recreational Problem," Rev. J. M. Walker, D.D.; "The Future of the Country Church," Dr. Rolvix Harlan; "The Relation of City and Country Churches," Rev. Goodridge A. Wilson, Jr., D.D.; "Youth and America the Beautiful," Rev. Henry W. McLaughlin, D.D. 1929 August 13 (Box 21)
  - Round Table: "The Economic and Industrial Development of the South"
    - "Is the South Following the Right Policy with Regard to Labor?," Dr. W. Jett Lauck; "A Survey of Southern Industrial Progress," Dr. Abraham Berglund 1929 August 6 (Box 21)
    - "Industrialism in the South," Homer Ferguson; "The Economic and Industrial Progress of the South," Richard Edmonds 1929 August 7 (Box 21)
    - "The Resources and Expansion of the Great South," E. A. Hults; "Natural Resources of the New South," Dr. H. J. Bryson; "A Program of Fish Husbandry," Lewis Radcliffe 1929 August 8 (Box 21)
    - "Industrialization of the South - Past and Present," Richard Edmonds; "Virginia in the Building," Maj. LeRoy Hodges 1929 August 10 (Box 21)
    - "State and Local Policies Encouraging Industries," Robert D. Ramsey; "Advantages of Workmen's Compensation," Dr. Robert H. Tucker 1929 August 15 (Box 21)
    - "Transportation in Relation to Southern Industrial Development," Hon. J. Gordon Bohannon; "Diversification and Decentralization in the South," George M. Rommel; "Is the South Following the Right Policy in Regard to Labor?," Rev. James Meyers; "Highway Transportation," Hon. Henry G. Shirley; "Is the South Pursuing the Right Policy Toward Labor?," Matthew Woll 1929 August 17 (Box 21)
  - Round Table: "Democracy as Operative in America"
    - "The Nature of Democracy," Dr. Robert Kent Gooch 1929 August 5 (Box 22)
  - Evening Addresses
    - "Religion in Public Affairs," Bishop Francis J. McConnell 1930 August 3 (Box 22)
    - Welcome Speech," John Garland Pollard; Welcome Address, Edwin A. Alderman 1930 August 4 (Box 22)
    - "The Role of the Social Sciences in an Advancing Civilization," Frank O. Lamden 1930 August 5 (Box 22)
    - "Government as Umpire Only," Julius H. Barnes 1930 August 6 (Box 22)
    - ["Federal Farm Board"], Carl Williams 1930 August 7 (Box 22)
    - "American Policy in Nicaragua," Dr. Charles C. Batchelder; "The New Regime in Colombia," Dr. J. Fred Rippy 1930 August 8 (Box 22)
    - "The Jeffersonian Ideals of Religious Liberty," Dr. Walter A. Maier 1930 August 9 (Box 22)
    - "The Gospel According to Christ's Enemies," Dr. J. Stuart Holden 1930 August 10 (Box 22)
    - "Is Democracy a Failure?," Dr. Will Durant 1930 August 11 (Box 22)
    - "Holding Companies and Regulation," Martin J. Insull 1930 August 12 (Box 22)
    - "Democracy and the Individual in a Machine Age," Norman Thomas 1930 August 13 (Box 22)
    - "Law Enforcement as Related to the 18th Amendment," Mrs. D. Leigh Colvin; "The Rural Church and the Community," Rev. Arthur W. Hewitt 1930 August 14 (Box 22)
    - "Address on Aviation," Edward S. Evans 1930 August 15 (Box 22)
  - Round Table: "Administration of Public Business"
    - Report 1930 August (Box 22)
    - "The Administration and the Legislature," Henry L. Shattuck 1930 August 6 (Box 22)
    - "The Administration and the Courts," Julius T. Muench 1930 August 8 (Box 22)
    - "The Civil Service in the Modern State," Carl J. Freidrich 1930 August 15 (Box 22)
  - Round Table: "Business and Government"
    - "Is Business Efficient?," Dr. Emory G. Hawk, Victor A. Olander 1930 August 4 (Box 22)
    - "Government Aid to Business," Edward Wiest; Summary 1930 August 8 (Box 22)
    - "Government Regulation of Business," John Bauer; "The Government in Business," Mason Manghum 1930 August 11 (Box 22)
    - "Government Ownership and Operation," Martin J. Insull; "The Case for Public Ownership and Operation," Norman Thomas; Discussion 1930 August 13 (Box 22)
    - "Shall Government Encourage Larger Business Units?," Donald Randall Richberg 1930 August 15 (Box 22)
  - Round Table: "National Country Life"
    - "Folk Schools: Their Adaptation to the United States," Olive Campbell; "College for Everyone," S. A. Mathiasen 1930 August 4 (Box 22)
    - "The Family Farm," Bradford Knapp; "Stating the Problem of the Small Farm," Dr. C. J. Galpin; "Small Scale Farming: The Outlook for the Small Farm," Hugh MacRae 1930 August 6 (Box 22)
    - "Rural Industries," Wheeler McMillen; "Rural Industries: their Economic and Social Importance in Country Life," Joseph Hyde Pratt 1930 August 8 (Box 22)
    - "Merchandising to Farmers: Extending Mercantile Advantages to Country People," C. R. Hoffer; "Merchandising to Farmers or Country People," William Newton Neff 1930 August 11 (Box 22)
    - "Rural Art: Developing Beauty in the Countryside," Wm. A. R. Goodwin, R.E. Hieronymus 1930 August 13 (Box 22)
    - "Man's Debt to Modern Medicine," Marvin F. Haygood; "Rural Health Work," Dr. L. L. Lumsden 1930 August 15 (Box 22)
  - Round Table: "The Country Church and World Affairs"
    - "Relation of the Country Church and School," Prof. C. C. Haun; "The Country Church and the Rural School," Dr. Dabney S. Lancaster 1930 August 5 (Box 22)
    - "The Country Church and the Cooperative Extension Service," H. W. Hochbaum; "The Country Church and the Agricultural Extension Service," Rev. Clarence Walters Lokey 1930 August 7 (Box 22)
    - "The Country Church and Literature of Country People," Prof. L. Riggleman, Dr. C.M. McConnell; "The County Free Public Library," Dr. Henry Read McIlwaine 1930 August 9 (Box 22)
    - "The Country Church and the Farm Family," Prof. William Hayne Mills, Rev. Edwin V. O'Hara 1930 August 12 (Box 22)
    - "Agricultural Missions and the Rural Church in Mission Lands," Dr. John Roisner; "The Country Church in Mission Lands," Rev. L. I. Moffett, D.D. 1930 August 14 (Box 22)
    - "The Country Church and World Peace," Dr. Rolvix Harlan; Address, Prof. Edwin L. Earp, Ph.D. 1930 August 16 (Box 22)
  - Round Table: "Economic and Industrial Development of the South"
    - "Labor," John E. Edgerton 1930 August 5 (Box 23)
    - "A Labor Policy for the South," Magnus W. Alexander 1930 August 7 (Box 23)
    - "The New Role of Public Ownership in the Power Industry," Prof. James C. Bonbright 1930 August 9 (Box 23)
    - "Industrial Power Policy for the South," Preston S. Arkwright 1930 August 12 (Box 23)
    - "A Foreign Trade Policy for the South," W. Jett Lauck 1930 August 14 (Box 23)
    - "Foreign Trade Policy for the South," Floyd W. Jefferson 1930 August 16 (Box 23)
  - Round Table: "Our Latin American Relations"
    - "Tangible Results of American Intervention in Haiti," W. W. Cumberland; "Intervention in Haiti," Franklyn Waltman, Jr. 1930 August 5 (Box 23)
    - "Cuba and the Platt Amendment," Prof. Leland H. Jenks, Gustavo Gutierrez; Summary 1930 August 7 (Box 23)
    - "Colombian Oil Legislation," R. B. Gaither; "The Growing Importance of Relations with Cuba," Prof. J. Fred Rippy; Summary 1930 August 9 (Box 23)
    - "Our Treaty Relations with Panama," Henry Kittredge Norton 1930 August 12 (Box 23)
    - "The Restriction of Mexican Immigration," Carlos E. Castenada; "The Problem of Mexican Immigration," Prof. J. Fred Rippy 1930 August 14 (Box 23)
    - "Latin America and the Monroe Doctrine," Dr. Adrian Recinos; "Latin America, the Monroe Doctrine, and the League of Nations," William Spence Robertson; Summary 1930 August 16 (Box 23)
    - Report 1930 August 12 16 (Box 23)
  - Round Table: "Reorganization of State Government"
    - "State Reorganization in the United States," Frank O. Lowden 1930 August 5 (Box 23)
    - "Reorganization in Massachusetts," Carl Raymond; "Reorganization of State Government in Massachusetts," Henry L. Shattuck 1930 August 7 (Box 23)
    - "Reorganization of State Government, with Special Reference to Virginia," Prof. Robert H. Tucker 1930 August 9 (Box 23)
    - "The Budget and Reorganization," J. H. Bradford, Harvey Walker 1930 August 12 (Box 23)
    - "Taxation and Reorganization," C.H. Morrissett 1930 August 14 (Box 23)
    - "Public Welfare and Reorganization," Dr. Frank Bane 1930 August 16 (Box 23)
  - Open Forum
    - "The Inequity of Injunctions," Victor A. Olander 1930 August 4 (Box 23)
    - "Economic Effect of Prohibition on Southern Industrial Development," C. O'Conor Goolrick 1930 August 5 (Box 23)
    - "The Government and Industrial Relations," Glenn A. Bowers 1930 August 6 (Box 23)
    - "Unlimited Agricultural Cooperation: Will It Prove an Effective Remedy for the Farmers' Economic Ills?," H.C. Taylor 1930 August 7 (Box 23)
    - "The Position of Women in the United States," Mrs. Burnita Shelton Matthews 1930 August 8 (Box 23)
    - "Reorganization of State Government," O. Max Gardner, Seabury C. Mastick 1930 August 9 (Box 23)
    - Address, James Brown Scott 1930 August 11 (Box 23)
    - "Government and Business in the Court of Domestic Relations," Oswald Garrison Villard 1930 August 12 (Box 23)
    - "Can and Should the Eighteenth Amendment Be Enforced?," Mrs. Marion Booth Kelley; "Prohibition Enforcement and Observance," Dr. Ernest H. Cherrington 1930 August 13 (Box 23)
    - "Canadian Liquor Control," Ben H. Spence 1930 August 14 (Box 23)
  - Round Table: "Consumers' Credit in America and Its Relation to Present and Future Prosperity"
    - "Consumers' Credit in America... ," H. L. Braham 1930 August (Box 23)
    - "Eligibility of Finance Company Paper for Rediscount," Milan V. Ayres 1930 August 7 (Box 23)
    - Report, Round Table: "National Country Life Questions," Dr. C. J. Galpin 1930 August 11-15 (Box 23)
    - Report, Round Table: "Economic and Industrial Development of the South," Major LeRoy Hodges 1930 August 5 9 (Box 23)
    - Report, Round Table: "Reorganization of State Government," Harry Flood Byrd 1930 August 16 (Box 23)
  - Evening Addresses
    - "Presentation of the Portrait of Dr. Maphis," Seymour M. Stone; "Acceptance of the Portrait of Dr. Maphis," Dr. Edwin A. Alderman 1930 August 11 (Box 23)
  - Round Table: "Regionalism"
    - "State Planning," Franklin D. Roosevelt 1931 July 6 (Box 24)
    - "Historical Considerations in Regional Planning," Charles W. Eliot II 1931 July 7 (Box 24)
    - "Regional Planning," Flavel Shurtleff; Lewis Mumford 1931 July 8 (Box 24)
    - "Cultural Aspects of Regionalism," Benton MacKaye, John Gould Fletcher 1931 July 9 (Box 23)
    - "Sociological and Economic Aspects of Regionalism," Prof. R. D. McKenzie; "The New Regionalism," Prof. R. D. McKenzie; "Sociological Aspects of Regionalism," Howard W. Odum 1931 July 10 (Box 24)
    - "The Concept of Planning," Stuart Chase 1931 July 11 (Box 24)
  - Round Table: "Unemployment"
    - "A Plan for a Law for Compulsory Dismissal Compensation" n.d. (Box 24)
    - "Unemployment as seen by Foreign Economists," Adamantios Th. Polyzoides 1931 July 6 (Box 24)
    - "Unemployment as an International Problem," Dr. Felix Morley 1931 July 7 (Box 24)
    - "Industrial Plans for Employment Stabilization and Unemployment Relief," Prof. T. Douglas Brown; "The Economic Background of the Present Depression," John P. Frey 1931 July 8 (Box 24)
    - "The Community and Unemployment," Dr. Joseph Willits 1931 July 9 (Box 24)
    - "Can National Planning Prevent Unemployment?" Sumner H. Slichter 1931 July 10 (Box 24)
    - Summary 1931 July 6-11 (Box 24)
    - Findings on Unemployment 1931 July 11 (Box 24)
    - Brief Bibliography on Unemployment 1931 July, 2 folders (Box 24)
  - Round Table: "Municipal Administration"
    - "State and Municipal Taxation," Dr. F.G. Crawford; "Relation of States to Municipal Taxation," R. W. B. Hart 1931 July 1 (Box 24)
    - "City Planning," Edward L. Stone 1931 July 3 (Box 24)
  - Round Table: "Law Enforcement"
    - "Do Police Protect the Public?," Bruce Smith 1931 June 29 (Box 24)
    - Report 1931 June 29-July 4 (Box 24)
    - "Racketeering," Robert Isham Randolph; Address, George Z. Medalie 1931 June 30 (Box 24)
    - "Prohibition and the Report of the President's Commission," J. W. Wadsworth, Jr.; "The Problem of Prohibition Enforcement," Oliver W. Stewart 1931 July 1 (Box 24)
    - "The Difficulties of Enforcement," Colonel A. W. W. Woodcock, John C. Gebhart 1931 July 2 (Box 24)
    - "Rewriting the Criminal Law," John Barker Waite; "Problems of the Magistrates Court," Judge Jonah J. Goldstein 1931 July 3 (Box 24)
  - Round Table: "The New Industrialism in the South"
    - "The New Industrialism in the South," LeRoy Hodges; "Southern Economic and Political Trends," Prof. Herman Clarence Nixon; "The Social Significance of the New Industrialism," Dr. Francis P. Gaines; Discussion Following Preliminaries 1931 July 6 (Box 24)
    - "Labor's Program in the New Industrialism," R. T. Bowden; Discussion Following Address of R. T. Bowden" 1931 July 7 (Box 24)
    - "Child Labor in the South," Donald Comer; "The Place of Women and Children in Southern Industry," Lucy Randolph Mason; Discussion Following Addresses 1931 July 8 (Box 24)
    - "The New Industrialism and Power Development in the South," John B. Reynolds, F. H. Newell; Discussion following Addresses 1931 July 9 (Box 24)
    - "New Industrialism in the South," Maj. R.S. Buck; "Foreign Trade and the Way to Economic Recovery in the South," R.S. MacElwee; Discussion Following Address of R. S. MacElwee; "Foreign Trade Versus High Tariffs," R. L. McKeller 1931 July 10 (Box 24)
    - Report, Samuel W. McIntosh; Address, Charles G. Mettler; "The New Industrialism and the South's Place in National Industrial Preparedness," Gen. Benedict Crowell; "National Industrial Preparedness," Hon. Frederick H. Payne; Report 1931 July 11 (Box 24)
  - Round Table: "Regionalism"
    - "State Planning," J. Gordon Bohannan 1931 July 6 (Box 25)
    - "Historical Consideration in Regional Planning," Henry Wright; "Statistical Engineering Methods in Regional Planning," Ernest P. Goodrich; "The Part Played by Thomas Jefferson in Securing, Planning, and Building the National Capitol and its Environs," T.S. Settle 1931 July 7 (Box 25)
    - "Cultural Aspects of Regionalism," Stringfellow Barr 1931 July 9 (Box 25)
  - Round Table: "Municipal Administration"
    - "Interesting the Taxpayer in His Government," William B. Munro, Frank C. Hanrahan 1931 July 1 (Box 25)
  - Round Table: "The Chain Store"
    - "The Chain Store and Its Retail Competitor," Dr. Clyde William Phelps; "The Chain Store and the Independent Merchant," M.M. Zimmerman 1931 July 6 (Box 25)
    - "The Chain Store and the Manufacturer and the Wholesaler," A.W. Hughes 1931 July 7 (Box 25)
    - "The Indiana Decision and Regulatory Laws Affecting Chain Stores" Clark McKercher 1931 July 8 (Box 25)
    - "The Chain Store and Management," Alvin Dodd 1931 July 9 (Box 25)
    - "The Chain Store and Management," George W. Alger; "The Chain Store and Public Policy," J. Frank Grimes; "The Chain Store Monopoly," Senator Smith W. Brookhart; "The Chain Store and Public Policy," Robert S. Marx 1931 July 10 (Box 25)
    - "What Principles of Organization Management Must Govern to Insure Efficient Voluntary Group Enterprise," J. Frank Grimes; "The Implications of the Supreme Court Decision in the Indiana Chain Store Case," Frank W. Wheeler; "The Chain Store and the Community," Paul H. Nystrom 1931 July 11 (Box 25)
  - Conference: "The Place of the Child in Public Affairs"
    - "The Place of the Child in Public Affairs," F. J. Kelly 1931 July 2 (Box 25)
    - "A Program for the Adjustment of Physically and of Mentally Handicapped Children in the United States," William J. Ellis 1931 July 3 (Box 25)
  - Monroe Centennial Memorial Exercises
    - "Aspects of the Monroe Doctrine," Hon. W.R. Castle, Jr.; "Maps Released with Castle's Address" 1931 July 4 (Box 25)
  - Monroe Centennial Memorial Exercises
    - "Aspects of the Monroe Doctrine," Hon. W.R. Castle, Jr.; "Maps Released with Castle's Address" 1931 July 4 (Box 25)
  - [Evening Address] "Institute of Institutes"
    - "Responsibilities of the Pan American Press," Charles Stephenson Smith; "The Press and the Radio in Cooperation with Institutes of Public Affairs," Dr. Victor Rosewater 1931 June 27 (Box 25)
  - Evening Addresses
    - Luther A. Weigle (empty) 1931 June 28 (Box 25)
    - "Welcome," Dean John Newcomb; "The Silver Lining of Our Politics," William B. Munro; "Public Personnel Administration and Good Government," Charles P. Messick 1931 June 29 (Box 25)
    - "The Folly of Prohibition," Mrs. Carroll Miller; "Give Prohibition a Chance," Mrs. Ella A. Boole 1931 June 30 (Box 25)
    - "Adult Education," Spencer Miller, Jr. 1931 July 1 (Box 25)
    - "Obstacles to Pan American Understanding," Herman G. James; "Startling Facts in Today's Economic Muddle," "Declaration of Interdependence of Men," Samuel S. Wyer 1931 July 2 (Box 25)
    - "Child Protection, A Public Concern," A. J. Carlson 1931 July 3 (Box 25)
    - "Evening Address," William E. Dodd (empty) 1931 July 4 (Box 25)
    - "Learning from the Master Teacher," Dr. Walter L. Single 1931 July 5 (Box 25)
    - "Excessive Cost of Local Government," Franklin D. Roosevelt; "Unemployment: A Review of the Position in Postwar Britain," Ben Bowen Thomas; "Cooperation vs. Chaos," T.L. Chadbourne 1931 July 7 (Box 25)
    - "Peace An Appeal to the Heroic," Dr. M. Ashby Jones; "A Peace Program for Patriots," Kirby Page 1931 July 8 (Box 25)
    - "Social Effects of Government Competition in Industry and Business," John Spargo; "Fundamental Faults of Compulsory Unemployment Insurance," Noel Sargent 1931 July 9 (Box 25)
    - "Political Parties and Issues Up to Date," Hon. Smith W. Brookhart; "The Challenge of Unemployment," Dr. Lillian Gilbreth 1931 July 10 (Box 25)
  - Conference on Adult Education
    - "The White House Conference: A Venture in Adult Education," F. J. Kelly; "The Practicing Physician and Adult Education," Dr. Greer Baughman 1931 July 1 (Box 25)
  - [Special Conference on Personnel]
    - "Classification and Compensation Plans," Ismar Baruch 1931 June 30 (Box 25)
  - Conference on County Government
    - "County Management," Prof. Paul W. Wager 1931 July 2 (Box 25)
  - Round Table: "Religious Education in the Rural Church"
    - "The Need for Religious Education in Rural Areas," Rev. C. C. Haun, George T. Waite 1931 June 29 (Box 25)
  - Round Table: "The Plight of Southern Agriculture"
    - "Farming A Mode of Life," H.G. Hastings 1931 June 30 (Box 25)
  - Round Table: "Religious Education in the Rural Church"
    - "A Curriculum of Religious Education in the Rural Church," Paul H. Vieth 1931 June 30 (Box 26)
    - "A Curriculum for Religious Education in the Rural Church," Dr. Albert Z. Mann 1931 June 30 (Box 26)
    - "Administering the Program of Religious Education," Dr. T. C. Currie; "Religious Education in the Country Church," Edwin E. Sundt; "A Program of Religious Education for Country People," R.A. Kilburn 1931 July 1 (Box 26)
    - "Town and Country Leadership," Dr. Ralph S. Adams; "Town and Country Church Leadership," Dr. William Archer Wright 1931 July 2 (Box 26)
    - "Vacation Bible Schools in Rural Areas," Rev. Victor C. Detty; "The Daily Vacation Bible School in Rural Areas," Rev. Clyde C. Walsh 1931 July 3 (Box 26)
    - "Weekday Religious Education in Rural America," Rev. Minor C. Miller, Walter Albion Squire, D.D. 1931 July 4 (Box 26)
  - Round Table: "Plight of Southern Agriculture"
    - "The Agriculture of the Southeastern States from a National Viewpoint," Hon. Carl Vrooman 1931 June 29 (Box 26)
    - "Education and Agriculture--Is Our Educational System Functioning Properly for the Restoration of Agriculture and Rural Civilization?," Bradford Knapp 1931 July 1 (Box 26)
    - "The Balance of Trade Against Southern Agriculture," S. H. Hobbs, Jr. 1931 July 2 (Box 26)
    - "The Forests in Relation to National Welfare and to the Prosperity of the South," Ernest A. Sterling 1931 July 3 (Box 26)
    - "The Base of the South's Economic Structure, An Obsolete System of Agriculture, Threatens its Civilization. The Chances for Saving it? The Method" Hugh MacRae; "The Importance of Demonstrations as a Factor in the Improvement of Agriculture," Dr. W. W. Long 1931 July 4 (Box 26)
  - Round Table: "Our Latin American Relations"
    - "The Significance of Recent Revolutions in Latin America," Earl James; "North American Opinion and the Latin American Revolutions," Paul Vanorden Shaw, Ph.D. 1931 June 29 (Box 26)
    - "Significance of the Growing Investment of United States Capital in Latin America," Dr. W. W. Cumberland, Dr. Max Winkler 1931 June 30 (Box 26)
    - "Race Relations in Latin America with Special Reference to the Development of Indigenous Culture," Ruediger Bilden; "Racial Problems in Peru: Past, Present, and Future," Philip Ainsworth Means 1931 July 1 (Box 26)
    - "A Program of Closer Cultural Relations with Latin America," Ernest Galarza 1931 July 2 (Box 26)
    - "Inter American Arbitration," John H. Latané; "The Progress of International Settlement on the South American Continent," James Oliver Murdock 1931 July 3 (Box 26)